[SINGING] Your website is unused because
[MÚSICA] Your website is unused because
your users are confused.
your users are confused.
Bad UI can be quite deadly.
Bad UI can be quite deadly.
Let's make it sweet and friendly.
Let's make it sweet and friendly.
Make buttons scale and skew.
Make buttons scale and skew.
Keyframes animate it too.
Keyframes animate it too.
Change color and use easing.
Change color and use easing.
The effect will be quite pleasing.
The effect will be quite pleasing.
Try rotations and translations in
Try rotations and translations in
Adventures in Web Animations.
Adventures in Web Animations.
Welcome back to level two in
Bem vindo de volta ao level dois de Adventures in Web Animations.
This section, we'll be talking about transforming rotate.
Nesta sessão, nós falaremos sobre rotação (transforming rotate).
CSS transforms let you modify elements
Transformações CSS permitem que você modifique elementos
in their coordinate space.
através de suas coordenadas no espaço.
They can be rotated, translated, scaled, and even skewed.
Eles podem ser rotacionados, transladados (translated), escalados (scaled), e até distorcidos (skewed).
In our application, something fun
Na nossa aplicação, algo divertido
to animate that's part of our UI could be this close icon on our
para animar, que é parte da nossa UI, pode ser este ícone de fechar
buy game form.
no formulário para comprar o game.
With transform, we can easily rotate this.
Com transform, nós podemos facilmente rotacionar isso.
We call out our modal close on hover
Nós chamamos nosso modal-close no hover
and we say transform rotate 360 degrees.
e nós dizemos transform rotate 360 degrees (graus).
Rotate takes any number value with a degree or a turn unit
Rotate recebe qualquer número com o sufixo degree (graus) ou
suffix.
turn (volta).
So transform rotate one turn is the same as 360 degrees.
Então transform rotate um turn é o mesmo que 360 degrees (graus).
Our icon on hover, though, is jumping from the start state
Nosso ícone, ao ser focado, no entanto, está pulando do estado inicial
immediately to the end state.
imediatamente para o estado final.
You don't actually get to see the rotation.
Atualmente você não consegue ver a rotação.
This is where transitions, yet again, come to the rescue.
Aqui é onde as transições, sim, denovo, vêm ao nosso resgate.
Inside our modal close's initial state,
Dentro do estado inicial do nosso modal-close,
we'll say transition transform four seconds.
nós diremos transition transform 4s.
Adding transition transform allows
Adicionar transition transform nos permite
us to see the icon changing on hover.
ver o ícone mudando ao ser focado.
So far, we've only been using the default timing function
Até agora, nós estavamos usando apenas a função de tempo padrão de
of ease on our transitions.
ease em nossas transições.
However, we have this full list here available to us.
No entanto, nós temos toda essa lista disponível para nós.
So if we go ahead and say transition transform
Se nós formos em frente e dissermos transition transform
four seconds and use ease out, for instance,
4s e usarmos ease out, por exemplo,
you'll see how the x icon rotates slower
você verá como o ícone x irá girar mais devagar
near the end of the animation.
próximo ao fim da animação.
Go ahead and try your hand at transforms,
Vá em frente e coloque a mão nos transforms,
and I'll see you in the next section.
e eu vejo você na próxima sessão.